Geraldine Farrar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music (Box 5-7)
  - Music By Other Composers
    - Farrar, Geraldine, arranger
      - My Favorite Songs, (Favorite Songs of Famous Singers Series). Boston: Oliver Ditson Company, 1916. (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Grétry, M.
      - Arie der Lucette aus "Silvain"., Score and Orchestra Parts, two sets, one handwritten in ink and one mimeographed. (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Wagner, Richard
      - Der Fünf Gedichte für eine Frauenstimme mit Pianofortebegleitung. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, n.d., Orchestrated by Felix Mottl; Includes: No. 3: Im Treibhaus (Studie zu Tristan und Isolde) No. 4: Schmerzen No. 5: Träume (Box-folder 7/3)
- Correspondence (Box 8-11)
  The correspondence in the collection consist of letters, picture postcards, telegrams, and various personal notes both to and from Geraldine Farrar. The materials reflect both her private and public life.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by correspondent.
  - Amato, Pasquale [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - America First (Box-folder 8/1)
  - American Red Cross (Box-folder 8/2)
  - American Society for Visual Education [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - American Women's Voluntary Services (Box-folder 8/3)
  - "A" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/4)
  - Belasco, David (Box-folder 8/5)
  - Belew, Kyrle (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Bell, Walter [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Bemberg, Herman (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Berlin, Königlichen Schauspiele (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Bernhardt, Sarah (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Bigelow, Poultney (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Bleech, Leo (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Bodanecky, Artur (Box-folder 8/12)
  - Borchers, Dr. H. [See: scrapbook: Box 34]
  - Bori, Lucrezia [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 8/13)
  - Brainard, Bertha (Box-folder 8/14)
  - Brandt, Marianne (Box-folder 8/15)
  - Businger, Ruth (1927-65) (Box-folder 8/16)
  - Businger, Ruth (re: biography) (Box-folder 8/17)
  - Businger, Ruth (misc. business) (Box-folder 8/18)
  - "B" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/19)
  - Calvé, Emma (Box-folder 8/20)
  - Carré, Albert (Box-folder 8/21)
  - Carreño, Teresa (Box-folder 8/22)
  - Caruso American Memorial Foundation (Box-folder 8/23)
  - Caruso, Enrico (Box-folder 8/24)
  - Cecilie, Crown Princess [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 8/25)
  - Charpentier, Gustave (Box-folder 8/26)
  - Clement, Edmond (Box-folder 8/27)
  - Consulate General of Germany [See also: scrapbook: Box 34] (Box-folder 8/28)
  - Cobb, Irvin S. (Box-folder 8/29)
  - Coward Poem Reactions (1943) (Box-folder 8/30)
  - Curtis, Arthur M. [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Cushing, Marc [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - "C" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/31)
  - Damrosch, Walter Johannes [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Davis, Robert H. (Box-folder 9/1)
  - De Luca, Giuseppe (Box-folder 9/2)
  - DeMille, Cecil B. (Box-folder 9/3)
  - Droescher, Georg (1909-41) (Box-folder 9/4)
  - Downes, Olin (Box-folder 9/5)
  - Dukas, Paul (Box-folder 9/6)
  - "D" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Eames, Emma (Box-folder 9/8)
  - Elliot, E.M. [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Ellis, Charles A. (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Emery, Ernest W. (Box-folder 9/10)
  - Finck, Henry T. (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Fiske, Minnie Maddern (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Fitch, Clyde (Box-folder 9/13)
  - Flagstad, Kirsten (Box-folder 9/14)
  - Freeman, Mrs. [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Fremstad, Olive (Box-folder 9/15)
  - Frohman, Daniel [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 9/16)
  - Fuller, A. T. (Box-folder 9/17)
  - "E-F" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 9/18)
  - Galli-Curci, Amelita (Box-folder 9/19)
  - Garden, Mary (Box-folder 9/20)
  - Gay, Marcia (Box-folder 9/21)
  - Gatti-Casazza, Giullio and Rosina [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 9/22)
  - General-Kommando III. Armee-korps (Germany) (Box-folder 9/29)
  - Gertz, Elmer (Box-folder 9/24)
  - Getzoff, Benjamin [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Greystone Press (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Goldwyn, Samuel (Box-folder 9/26)
  - Gounod, Charles (Box-folder 9/27)
  - Guilbert, Yvette (Box-folder 9/28)
  - Gunsbourg, Raoul (Box-folder 9/29)
  - "G" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 9/30)
  - Hadley, Henry (Box-folder 9/31)
  - Hahn, Reynaldo (Box-folder 9/32)
  - Hesse, Almor Vangel [See: scrapbook: Box 39]
  - Holmes, E, Burton (Box-folder 9/39)
  - Houghton Mifflin (Box-folder 9/34)
  - Hughes, Rupert (Box-folder 9/35)
  - Humperdinck, Engelbert (Box-folder 9/36)
  - Humphries, Daisy ("Dadums") (Box-folder 9/37)
  - Hurst, Ernie (Box-folder 9/38)
  - "H" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 9/39)
  - Internationale Stiftung, Salzburg [See: Mozarteum]
  - Irwin, Mary [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Japanese student (anonymous) (Box-folder 9/40)
  - Jerome, William Travers (Box-folder 9/41)
  - Johnson, Edward [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Kaulback, Friedrich August von (Box-folder 9/42)
  - Kent, Rockwell (Box-folder 9/25)
  - Key, Pierce V.R. (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Klan, Marc (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Krause, Otto [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - "I-K" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 10/3)
  - La Grant, Earle W. [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Lambert Company (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Lara, Isidora de (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Le Gallienne, Eva (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Lehmann, Lilli (1904-15) (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Lehmann, Lilli (1919-29) (Box-folder 10/8)
  - Lehmann, Lotte [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 10/9)
  - Leoncavallo, Berthe (Box-folder 10/10)
  - Long, John Luther (Box-folder 10/11)
  - Mack, Willard (Box-folder 10/12)
  - Marlowe, Julia (Box-folder 10/13)
  - Martens, Frederick Hermann (Box-folder 10/14)
  - Martinelli, Giovanni (Box-folder 10/15)
  - Massenet, Jules (Box-folder 10/16)
  - Maulsby, Ann (Box-folder 10/17)
  - McBride, Mary Margaret (Box-folder 10/18)
  - McCormack, John (Box-folder 10/19)
  - McCormack, Mrs. John (Box-folder 10/20)
  - Melba, Nellie (Box-folder 10/21)
  - Melchior, Lauritz [See: scrapbook: Box 33, Box 42]
  - Metropolitan Opera Company, New York (Box-folder 10/22)
  - Miller, Mrs. Bernard [See: scrapbook: Box 34]
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 10/23)
  - Moscher, Florence (Box-folder 10/24)
  - Mozarteum (Box-folder 10/25)
  - Murat, Princess (Box-folder 10/26)
  - Musical Courier (Box-folder 10/27)
  - Muzio, Claudia (Box-folder 10/28)
  - "M" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 10/29)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (Box-folder 10/30)
  - Nast, Condé (Box-folder 10/31)
  - National Broadcasting Company (Box-folder 10/32)
  - Neuer, Berthold [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - New England Conservarory of Music (Box-folder 10/33)
  - New York Tribune (Box-folder 10/34)
  - Nordica, Lillian (Box-folder 10/35)
  - Novotna, Jarmila (Box-folder 10/36)
  - "N" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 10/37)
  - Oppenheimer, Mildred R. (Box-folder 10/38)
  - Paris Opéra (Box-folder 10/39)
  - Peroni, Carlo (Box-folder 10/40)
  - Peterson, Dr. and Mrs. F. [See: scrapbook: Box 34]
  - Pickford, Mary (Box-folder 10/41)
  - Plançon, Pol (Box-folder 10/42)
  - Poet (anonymous) (Box-folder 10/43)
  - Political Correspondence [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 10/44)
  - Pons, Lily [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 10/45)
  - Ponselle, Rosa Melba [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 11/1)
  - Prisoner (anonymous) (Box-folder 11/2)
  - Puccini, Giacomo (Box-folder 11/3)
  - Rachmaninoff, Sergei and Natalie [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 11/4)
  - Raisa, Rosa (Box-folder 11/5)
  - Republican National Committee [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Rogers, James H. (Box-folder 11/6)
  - Rostand, Edmond (Box-folder 11/7)
  - "O-R" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Scharf, Bernard W. [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Schirmer, Rudolph E. (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Schumann-Heink, Ernestine (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Sembrich, Marcela [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 11/11)
  - Sheldon, Edward (Box-folder 11/12)
  - Slezak, Leo (Box-folder 11/13)
  - Smith, Delos Jr. [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - Spanuth, August (Box-folder 11/14)
  - Stockholm Opera (Box-folder 11/15)
  - Stokowski, Olga Samaroff (Box-folder 11/16)
  - Strauss, Richard (Box-folder 11/17)
  - Sturgis, David [See: scrapbook: Box 33]
  - "S" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 11/18)
  - Takaoki, Sumiko (Box-folder 11/19)
  - Taylor, Deems (Box-folder 11/20)
  - Tempest, Marie (Box-folder 11/21)
  - Thompson, Samuel S. (Box-folder 11/22)
  - Thorburg, Kerstin (Box-folder 11/23)
  - Thursby, Emma Cecelia (Box-folder 11/24)
  - Torrey, George Burroughs (Box-folder 11/25)
  - Toscanini, Arturo [See: scrapbook: Box 33, Box 42]
  - Universal Pictures Corporation (Box-folder 11/26)
  - U. S. Army, Women's Army Corps (Box-folder 11/27)
  - U. S. Government, Office of Civil Defense (Box-folder 11/28)
  - U. S. Government, Office of Price Administration (Box-folder 11/29)
  - Huelsen, Von [See: Berlin, Königlichen Schauspiele]
  - "T-V" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 11/30)
  - Waller, Frank Laird (Box-folder 11/31)
  - Webb, Annie B. (Box-folder 11/32)
  - Whitcomb, Lois Elisabeth [See: scrapbook: Box 42]
  - Wiggin, Kate Douglass ("Katydid") (Box-folder 11/33)
  - Wilhelm, Crown Prince (1929-41) [See also: scrapbook: Box 33] (Box-folder 11/34)
  - Wilhelm, Crown Prince (1945-51) (Box-folder 11/35)
  - Wilhelm II, Kaiser (Box-folder 11/36)
  - Wilkie, Mrs. Wendell (Box-folder 11/37)
  - Wright, Mrs. Earl D. [See: scrapbook: Box 39]
  - Wolff, Albert (Box-folder 11/38)
  - "W-Z" - miscellaneous (Box-folder 11/39)
  - Zenatello,Giovanni [See: Gay, Marcia]
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 11/40)
  - Unidentified [See also: scrapbook: Box 33, Box 39] (Box-folder 11/41)
- Contracts, 1908-1919 (Box 12)
  Farrar's contracts with the Metropolitan Opera from 1908 to 1918 comprise the bulk of the Contracts series. There are also a considerable amount of film contracts with the Goldwyn Pictures Corporation, dating from 1915 to 1919.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by corporate body.
  - American Piano Company (Box-folder 12/1)
  - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Anderson, E.H. (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Associated Exhibitors, Inc. (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Claggett, Benjamin F. (Box-folder 12/5)
  - Comité de l'Assocìation de Secour Mutuels entre les Artistes Dramatiques (Box-folder 12/6)
  - Ellis, C.A. (Box-folder 12/7)
  - Foley, Charles J. (Box-folder 12/8)
  - German Government (Box-folder 12/9)
  - Goldfish, Samuel (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Goldwyn Pictures Corporation (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Greystone Press, Inc. (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company (Box-folder 12/13)
  - Jesse L. Lasky Feature Play Company (Box-folder 12/14)
  - Metropolitan Opera Company, New York (Box-folder 12/15)
  - Peat, Harold R. (Box-folder 12/16)
  - New England Concert Company (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Victor Talking Machine Company (Box-folder 12/18)
  - Contract-related materials, Folders: 12/19: Itineraries (Concert Tours) 12/20: Receipts (miscellaneous) (Box-folder 12/19-20)
- Scripts (Box 13-15)
  Scripts of radio programs and pageants appear in both manuscript and typescript forms and reflect Farrar's career as a musical commentator for various radio programs and as a volunteer in civic organizations after her retirement from opera singing. The majority of the scripts are from the years 1934 and 1935.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by title.
  - Aïda (Box-folder 13/1)
  - American Radiator Company - "Sunday Evenings" (Box-folder 13/2)
  - Damrosch Concert (20 January 1935) (Box-folder 13/3)
  - Caruso Memorial (25 February 1935) (Box-folder 13/4)
  - Die Walküre (Box-folder 13/5)
  - Don Giovanni (Box-folder 13/6)
  - Don Pasquale (Box-folder 13/7)
  - La Forza del Destino - Ponselle (Box-folder 13/8)
  - General Electric Show (Box-folder 13/9)
  - Handel and Bach (1938 Metropolitan Christmas Broadcast) (Box-folder 13/10)
  - Hänsel und Gretel (Box-folder 13/11)
  - Lily Pons (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Lucia di Lammermoor (Box-folder 14/2)
  - Palmolive - "Stars of the Future" Audition (Box-folder 14/3)
  - Pre-Season (Metropolitan Opera 1934-35) (Box-folder 14/4)
  - Red Cross (1 of 2) (Box-folder 14/5)
  - Red Cross (2 of 2) (Box-folder 14/6)
  - Romeo et Juliette (Box-folder 14/7)
  - La Serva Padrona (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Simone Boccanegra (Box-folder 15/2)
  - La Sonnambula - Bori (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Tannhäuser (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Tibbet, Laurence - Interview (Box-folder 15/5)
  - La Traviata (Box-folder 15/6)
  - Tristan et Isolde - Martinelli (Box-folder 15/7)
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 15/8)
  - WEAF Radio Station (Box-folder 15/9)
  - WOR Radio Station (Box-folder 15/10)
  - WQXR Radio Station (Box-folder 15/11)
  - WTIC Radio Station (Box-folder 15/12)
- Programs, 1895-1934, undated (Box 16)
  The programs in the collection date from Farrar's first recitals in Melrose, Massachusetts, during her teenage years to her final appearances as a concert singer in 1931.
  Arrangement is chronological by date.
  - 1895-1908 (Box-folder 16/1)
  - 1910-1918 (Box-folder 16/2)
  - 1918-1921 (Box-folder 16/3)
  - 1921 (Box-folder 16/4)
  - 1922-1927 (Box-folder 16/5)
  - 1928-1930 (Box-folder 16/6)
  - 1931-1934 (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Undated Programs (Box-folder 16/8)
- Awards and Certificates (Box 17)
  The awards and certificates date from the last forty years of Farrar's life and contain those related to her many civic and artistic activities, including her ASCAP and Society of American Arts and Letters membership certificates.
  Arrangement is by format.
  - Awards and Certificates (Alphabetical by Organization) (Box 17)
- Clippings (Box 17)
  The Clippings series consists of cut sections from various periodicals and newspapers.
  - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 17)
- Scrapbooks, 1898-1941 (Box 18-46)
  The overwhelming majority of materials in the collection is found in 43 scrapbooks that cover Farrar's entire life and career.
  - 1898 and before (Box 18)
  - 1901-1910 (Box 18)
  - 1903-1904 (Box 19)
  - 1905-1908 (Box 20)
  - 1905-1934 (Box 27)
  - 1906-1908 (Box 20)
  - 1907-1908 (Box 21)
  - 1908-1909 (Box 22)
  - 1908-1910 (one of two) (Box 19)
  - 1908-1910 (two of two) (Box 23)
  - 1909-1910 (one of two) (Box 23)
  - 1909-1910 (two of two) (Box 24)
  - 1909-1910 (Box 24)
  - 1910 (Box 25)
  - 1910-1911 (Box 25)
  - 1910-1912 (one of three) (Box 26)
  - 1910-1912 (one of three) (Box 26)
  - 1910-1912 (one of three) (Box 29)
  - 1910-1930 (Box 28)
  - 1911-1915 (Box 29)
  - 1912-1914 (one of two) (Box 26)
  - 1912-1914 (two of two) (Box 26)
  - 1914-1919 (Box 39)
  - 1915 (Box 30)
  - 1916 (Box 30)
  - 1917-1918 (Box 30)
  - 1917-1935 (Box 30)
  - 1919 (one of two) (Box 40)
  - 1919 (two of two) (Box 41)
  - 1919-1920 (Box 42)
  - 1919-1921 (Box 43)
  - 1919-1921 (unboxed scrapbook) (Box 44)
  - 1920-1925 (unboxed scrapbook) (Box 45)
  - 1922-1923 (unboxed scrapbook) (Box 46)
  - 1931-1932 (Box 31)
  - 1932 (Box 32)
  - 1933-1935 (Box 33)
  - 1934-1935 (unboxed scrapbook) (Box 36)
  - 1935-1936 (Box 33)
  - 1937 (Box 34)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 35)
  - 1938-1941 (one of two) (Box 36)
  - 1938-1941 (two of two) (Box 37)
  - 1938-1939 (Box 38)
- Civic Materials (Box 47)
  The civic materials in the collection contain an assortment of governmental papers, forms, and notes, such as an auto log-book and lists of telephone numbers. These materials represent Farrar's participation in the Red Cross and various governmental organizations during World War II.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by organization.
  - American Red Cross (one of two) (Box-folder 47/1)
  - American Red Cross (two of two) (Box-folder 47/2)
  - Aircraft Notes (Box-folder 47/3)
  - American Women's Voluntary Service, Inc. (Box-folder 47/4)
  - B. and P.W. President's Special Fund (Box-folder 47/5)
  - Blood Bank (Box-folder 47/6)
  - Girl Scouts (Box-folder 47/7)
  - Ground Observer Corps (Box-folder 47/8)
  - Motor Corps Auto Log Book (one of two) (Box-folder 47/9)
  - Motor Corps Auto Log Book (one of two) (Box-folder 47/10)
  - Motor Corps Emergency List (Box-folder 47/11)
  - Office of Price Administration (Box-folder 47/12)
  - War Price and Rationing Boards (Box-folder 47/13)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 47/14)
- Photographs and Iconography (Box 48-52, 56-57)
  The photographs in the collection document Farrar's entire life and career. In addition to the many individual photographs, there are also two boxes of photographs (box 49, folders 5-8 and box 50) that were originally bound in two scrapbooks containing only photographs.
  - Farrar alone (in approximate chronological order) (one of three) (Box-folder 48/1)
  - Farrar alone (two of three) (Box-folder 48/2)
  - Farrar alone (three of three) (Box-folder 48/3)
  - Farrar in various opera roles (Box-folder 48/4)
  - Farrar with others (Red Cross Photographs) (Box-folder 48/5)
  - Farrar with others (Box-folder 48/6)
  - Photos without Farrar, includes signed photos of Massenet, Lilli Lehman, Wolf-Ferrari, and Saint-Saëns. Also includes miscellaneous Red Cross Photographs and photographs of the Kaiser's family that were in the box sealed until 1979. (Box-folder 48/7)
  - Photographs of various musicians (Box-folder 49/1)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs (Box-folder 49/2)
  - Drawings of Farrar (magazine covers) (Box-folder 49/3)
  - Miscellaneous Iconography (Box-folder 49/4)
  - Farrar in Opera roles, originally in scrapbook (original order preserved) (Box-folder 49/5-8)
  - Two bound volumes of photographs (Box 50)
  - Six folders of photos removed from scrapbook, in original order (also 3 books of stills from Farrar's silent films) (Box 51-52)
  - Miscellaneous iconography (oversize) (Box 56-57)
- Miscellany (Box 53-55, 58)
  Miscellaneous items relating to Farrar's life and career. These include several fans used by Farrar in Madama Butterfly, a framed portion of the curtain from the old Metropolitan Opera house given to her in 1940, copies of the New Testament, as well as several medals and awards for her public service activities.